Take a look at the name of the insurance company,
Axis Max Life Insurance, the
name of the policy holder is Sunil, this is his date of
birth 105 1997, non-smoker, this is his
phone number, he is
taking a pure term plan of Rs 2 crore, the term has come and gone for
33 years, he is present 27, so
he has taken this plan till he turns 60, he
pays the monthly premium, if you look at the premium, it is
₹1365, we are opening another tab, this is
also the same company, Axis Max Life
Insurance, same person, Sunil, date of
birth, non-smoker, phone number,
you can see everything, so the coverage is the same, the term is the
same, how many years to pay, it is
also the same, 60 years, but if you look at the premium, it is
₹3854, what is the same, the company is the same, the person is the same, everything is the same,
even if you look at the difference, if
you look at the difference, it is ₹3854, what is the difference?  Here is
₹2489 every month that person has to pay so much money
so if he dies the
family will get only two crores but why is there such a
difference? Many people
are making this mistake. They are paying unnecessarily high premium every month or every year.
After watching this video, they
will not make these mistakes at all. In this video, how to choose a good policy and what
riders should be added.
We do not need any riders. I
will tell you all this. So watch this video till the end.
Also, if you have not subscribed to this channel yet,
subscribe now. I am your Kaushik. If there is
any cheapest life insurance policy, it is definitely a
pure term insurance policy
because in this pure term insurance
policy, the coverage is very high and the
premium is very low. So,
who should definitely take this pure
term plan? First of all,
those who have dependence should definitely take it. Dependence
means for  For example, in your family, you are the
only one earning, you have a wife and
children, and your parents are
retired and are
idle at home. They cannot do any work.
Your wife is also a housewife. So in that case,
you should definitely take this
term plan. Why is it that no one earns?
You are the only one earning. Your entire household is spent on you. If
you are not there in the future,
what will be the family situation? They may be in a situation where they have to go down the road.
For example, you
have taken a term plan of two crores,
but if something happens to you, the
insurance company will give two crores to your family. So
even if you are not there, your family will be financially strong. Do you
understand? There is still a second
case.
Dependency is coming in the future. That is, you have recently
completed your studies, got a job,
settled, so you want to get
married in a few months in the future.
So if you get married, you may be a
housewife. You may get a wife who does not work.
Similarly, children will definitely
depend on you.  Your parents are
present but they are doing some job
but it is small so they will retire very soon and
after retirement they may depend on you
so even in such a case
even if you think that dependency is going to come in the future it is better for you to take it so you have
settled recently so your age is low and also you cannot have any major bad habits and there are no diseases
your age is low so there are no diseases no
bad
habits so now the premium will
be low this same premium will
continue for life long for example now
suppose the premium is 16000 per year so this same
16000 will be for life long do you understand
so people like you also take it now it is
very good and third case there
are a lot of debts for example for example you
mortgaged your house and borrowed a
lot from moneylenders for two rupees interest in the same way you mortgaged
your fields and
borrowed money
people like you should definitely take it why if
something happens to us tomorrow morning what will they do if
we mortgage our house because we have mortgaged it they will
say  That's all, we have
put those fields to work, we have done it ourselves,
then they will take the fields, just like our
family
has a home loan, you have taken a home loan of two crores, the
elders bought you,
so you left, then the bank comes and
these girls can't pay, so our family
bank comes and takes possession of the house,
so such people should also
definitely take it. Recently, if we are
taking a home loan, they are the ones who are
saying, sir, you should definitely take a term insurance
or come along with a home loan,
take a term plan of two crores, they
are saying that they will give a home loan only if you take a term plan. If you
already have a policy, there is
no need to take a second home loan along with it.
If not, what will they do? For
example, suppose you have applied for a 50 lakhs home loan,
three lakhs, three
lakhs premium, for a policy with a coverage of two crores, they
will take it all at once, let's say
three lakhs at once, so
what will they do? 50 lakhs home loan
plus 3 lakhs insurance  If
you have a total premium of 53 lakhs, you will be
sanctioned a loan. If you have a 50 lakhs home loan and 3
lakhs, do you understand the insurance premium?
Or let's say your EMI is
50000. So let's say 50000 emi plus
insurance premium is added to the EMI. Let's say
3000 premium. Let's say monthly
example, so 3000, so 53000. If you have an
EMI,
you will be
sanctioned a home loan of 50 lakhs. If
you want to get this loan now, you will have to
pay 300000 insurance premium at once. Do you
understand? That's how
banks are imposing it. If you already have an
insurance plan in your name, it is
not necessary. They demand that you
only give it if you take it. You don't need it
according to the rules. If you already have it, do you
understand? Now
I will show you how to check the good plan.  After
recording, I
will show you my video like this. I have
given a link in the description below the video.
Here is the term plan that you are watching. Click on it. If you
click on it, the
Policy Bazaar website
will open like this. Why is this website? Here we
can compare 51 insurance
companies are listed on this website.
So we can filter and compare and
get a good policy. So
after clicking, it will come like this.
Here we have to give our date of birth, phone number,
all correctly. Here you have
omitted the date of birth. For example, there is something
different in the Aadhaar card and PAN card. Suppose you have given something different here. In
the future, when
your family
applies for a claim, then they will
definitely ask for the Aadhaar card and PAN card. There is a
date of birth. Here, if the date of birth is
wrong, they will not give it. They will not give the claim. So that is why
it is very important.
Give everything correctly and click on View Plans. Do you understand?
All the plans will
come here.  51 insurance companies are
visible here, do you understand? So
before this, you will get this. After coming, it
will ask you if you have a smoking habit. If yes, then
you have to enter it by saying yes.
Similarly, how much is your income? How much income do
you have to enter correctly? For example, if it
is in the middle of 15 to 24,
click because in many cases,
ITR is asked for income tax returns.
So they check it.
If your
income is very low, many
insurance companies do not give you a term plan. Do
you understand that
you have to give every information, such as your graduate and salary?
So after coming, this page
will open. Back will come like this.
So first, we have to check
how much coverage is required. For example, if
you have two crores, if
something happens to you, the
insurance company will give two crores to your family.  How much coverage do
we need? So as per the rule, our annual
income is 20 times,
but in general it is 10 times. I
say 20 times because our income is
increasing and along with that,
inflation is certain. So if
we keep that in mind, it is
better to take 20 times. For
example, let's say your annual
income is 10 lakhs. 10 lakhs * 20
to CR. So it is better for you to choose a coverage of two crores.
For example, your annual income is
15 lakhs. If
you are earning 15 lakhs per year, let's say
15 lakhs *
20. How many three years? So then
you have to choose three years. For example, if
your income is 10 lakhs, but you have debts, there are
a lot of debts. In that case,
take 3 CR instead of 2 CR. So, depending on your
situation, how many people are dependent on you?  Whether
there are debts or not,
you should decide based on that. What I am
saying is that you should look at 20 times of your
annual income, so 10 times of income, so 2
CR, and
along with that, how long should
this term plan run until we reach our age?
Some people say that we should invest till 85 years, 90
years, 99 years. What
I am saying is that 60 years, 60
years, you should invest till you reach 60 years.
Why? When we reach 60
years, our children will be settled,
working or
doing business. They will not depend on us. By that time,
they will stand on their own feet financially. At that time,
our wife will be the same. Since we have
reached 60 years, we will
get money from the retirement fund, this PF, so that is how our life will be spent.
Who will not depend on us when we reach that age?
If you have invested for 90 years,
they will
My father has a term plan till 90 years, if
anything happens, he will
get one or two crores, there are people who
think like that,
I have seen such people myself. So what I am saying is that it is enough
till 60 years, it is not necessary,
after that, no one will depend on us, it will
be extra,
even after they settle down, these
two crores are not necessary, what is the real
penance? If we do not have it, our
family should not suffer financially, that is all, they
are going to school to get a job, they are settling down, children, wife, house wife, if
I am not there, how will they
take so many, so when we reach 60 years,
they will stand on their feet,
our wife will have some corpus, we do
not need this PF from anywhere, so if you ask me, 60 is
enough, if you have invested till 90 years,
then the
premium will definitely be higher. Similarly,
many people in this case say that they should
take return of premium,
so here are the
plans that return my premium.  Let
's click, before clicking, you should see
how much ICICI Prudential is. Two
crores. How much will we have till we reach 60 years?
Now click on 1377 per month.
Let's see what will change. 1377 is it now? Now see if it has changed to
2699. The same extra money we have. If we
invest in equity mutual funds for 33 years for that tenure, we will get a lot. Let's
show you a small example. How much did we have before? Now let's say
2700. Let's say 2700. So I
opened the calculator.
2700 minus how much is the amount. So the amount is
1377.
1377. That is, how much
more 1323 should be paid per month? For how many years? For 33
years? So let's do this 1323
sip. Let's see
how much money we will get if we do a mutual fund SIP. We should
look at it like this:
1323 So tenure.  Look at 33 years, 67
lakhs, do you understand? We invested
523908, but if we look at the return, 62
lakhs plus all the return will
come to 6739359, but if we
look at it here, if we live, if we live
for 60 years,
how much will we get? Let's
click on return, and
we will get 1022000. Whatever we have paid, we will get back, how much will we get?
1022000. Do you understand? There is no need for
return of premium, no need for pure
term insurance policy. How does it work? That is, no matter
how much we pay, if we live
until that tenure, if we live, not a
single rupee will be returned.
That is the purpose. If we want to get back everything we have paid after that tenure, we have to
check this.
So if we set this option, the
premium will automatically increase. Monthly
premium. So what I am saying is,
look at pure.  If we do SIP with this extra amount,
we will get this much money. Just don't
lose this much money for this 10 lakhs. Don't
lose 67 lakhs for 10 lakhs. What is the purpose? If
we don't, the money should go to the family.
That's all. The premium should be low and the coverage should be
high. So
I am strongly saying that you should look at this. There is
no return of premium. For example, you have invested in
return of premium.
After 10 years, the person who took the policy
died. So what is the return of premium? He
did not invest in return of premium. He
paid ₹1377 per month. After 10 years, he died. So what is the return of premium? He
paid
more money. So who is the one who has more coverage? So if
you follow this strictly, I am
saying that if you
want, you can
invest monthly if you want, you can invest annually too. If you take care of it
annually, if you
take care of ICI, then 16125 is the monthly amount. Do you
understand?  If
you look at it, it is your choice, monthly,
yearly, or it is your choice. So the main thing is
what we can do on this website, that is, we
can filter.
Here is the filter. First, we should
note the
climb settlement ratio. This climb settlement ratio should be
more than 95% and the
plan we are choosing should have the highest max to max
climb settlement
ratio. So here, apply the
filter for the climb settlement ratio high to low.
Here, the climb settlement ratio for HDFC Life
is 100%, 100. And
remember, the company we are choosing should have been around for a long time. It should not have come recently.
For example,
a company has come recently. So
who are the customers? They will be there for 20 years,
30 years,
who will be the customers for 40 years. For example,
one or two people died. So two people
died.  That company gave climb to both of them,
so the climb settlement ratio
is 100%. So what I am saying is that whatever
company is there, that company should be
in the market since forever. They should have
credibility. You should check that. Do you
understand? If some pitch company comes and says, "We said 100% blindly, right?" Don't
take it. Now HDFC is good. It has been there since forever.
Axis is good. You should
compare like this. Do you understand? For example, the main thing is that
you can filter the price here.
For example, if this company
looks at two crores, all the coverage is the
same. So if you look at the price, it is 2100. If
this company looks at 1400. What is the
difference? This is 2100. But if you look at this, it is 1400. Is there a
difference? If you look at this, it is 17. If you
look at this, it is
18. If you look at this, it is 1200.
We should look at all these.  Along with the climb settlement
ratio, what is the solvency ratio
and the price price should also be good.
So here I am
removing the filter. Okay, I have applied popularity. Let's see if
this plan is ours.
This is ICICI Prudential. I have clicked on it. Here,
many people are getting lost.
For example, here we have
two options. One is regular pay. The
other is limited pay. Do you understand? If we
look at regular pay, how many years should we pay?
We have to pay 33 years. What he is saying is that as
I said, instead of 33 years, you just have to
pay 10 years.
Everything else is paid. But the condition is that
you have to pay more. The
monthly premium is
higher because we are talking about monthly premium.
So the higher the premium, the more you have to
pay regularly. How much is ₹1377? 1377? Don't pay
more. Pay 3000.
Pay 136.  They say that instead of ₹137, if you
pay it like that, if you pay it for 10 years, it will be enough, if you
pay it for 10 years, it will be enough, if you pay it for everything else, you don't have to pay anything else. So if you
compare the two, you will save
₹167000. So, if
we
pay it regularly, we will pay a total of 6 lakhs. If we pay it like this, if we
pay the premium for just 10 years, we will
pay just ₹436000, that is, you will save ₹167000.
Many
people are falling into this trap and trying this. What
I am saying is, pay
this,
pay ₹1377 every month. Let's see the difference. Now, if you
open the calculator, how much is
₹3136?
1377? How much is
1759? Why pay more? Let's say that this amount is for
10 years, just 10 years.
1759. Here it is.  1700 59 If
you invest in these mutual funds for 10 years,
you will get 4 lakhs. Where
else can you save? If you
invest in mutual funds, the difference is that
after 10 years,
we will get four lakhs. This is
not the calculation of savings. So do this. So if
you make this a habit and continue this policy for 33 years,
how many years will you get?
Approximately 90 lakhs. 90
lakhs. Do you understand? For example,
you have chosen this, you have chosen limited
pay and invested it for 10 years,
so 60 years have come, which means that we will not
die in the term. So we will not get a
single rupee back. In fact,
even if we pay more premium, everything else will be
empty for 10 years.  We are not getting a
single rupee back, so if you
choose regular regular and
invest extra amount in mutual funds, you will
get 90 lakhs at least after you turn 60, do you understand? For
example, you have been paying high premium, you have paid for five
years,
after five years there was a risk and you
died, so you have paid high premium, so you
choose limited pay and you have
paid high premium, do you get
more coverage, so you have paid this much, you have paid
regular, for example, a
person named XYZ, another
person has taken regular, he
died at the same time, so then he
told him that he paid more than CRA and you will not get more, do you
understand? So it is
better to take regular and invest extra amount
in mutual funds,
saying that it is very good, my opinion is proceed,
here is all our information  We have to
give it correctly. Here, the income has to be
given correctly because we have to submit our IT returns
correctly. So, if we
find out there and make any mistake, proceed. Look,
we have already
avoided this. But he is
showing it again. He says, take limited pay.
So what do some people do? They are
tempted here again. Isn't it true that if you
pay for 10 years, you will save a lot of money?
How much is the present?
₹137. If you switch to this, you will
see the increase.
3136. Do you understand? So please don't look at this.
Many people are making such mistakes.
Look, look, it has changed. If we
pay for 10 years, no, no. We have gone back 33 years. Let's
see if the next option is ours. Look, what he is saying here is that
we have come back. We have
looked at 33 years. So it has
decreased again. ₹1377. What he is saying here is that if
something happens to you and your family, will you give
two crores to your family at once?
Or what they do, fearing that they
will spend two crores, instead of
giving one
crore rupees at once and giving 8333 rupees every month for
10 years, do you understand? The
option is not two crores at once, but one
crore rupees at once and giving
833 every month for 10 years. We can check it if we want,
but no next option
comes and every month
₹167000 for 10 years, after we die,
every month ₹167000 will be deposited
in our family bank account for
10 years. If
you ask me, don't do all this, just give the same two crores to the family at once and check it out.
Tell your family clearly if I
go, here is the document here, I
put it in the beer. If I go, if you
take the policy from the policy bazaar, you will get the policy at a discount. There is a
discount of up to 15%. The policy will be at a discount.
So even after you take the policy from the policy bazaar,
this  If the document
is original, the
insurance company will come to your house and show that
document clearly to the family.
Chandi, I
have put this here, if there is any risk for me,
here is the number of the relationship manager. If you
call and
talk to them, everything will be
fine. So if something
happens, your family will go and
inform the insurance company and they will give you two crores at
once. So after getting two crores, listen to me
now.
Take these two crores and make an FD. If it is
not safe, you can take the help of a financial advisor and
invest. But to be
safe, if you
make an FD of two crores, let's see how much you will get.
For example, let's say
you have two crores in this bank. You have
made a two-year FD. So you
need money for every quarter's expenses. You
can check this option so that the money is deposited in your family's bank account every quarter. This is
called non-cumulative. Do you understand? So if you
deposit two crores at once and
see that the money is deposited every quarter,
how much will it cost you each quarter?  Quarter 362500
Your original two crores whatever it is will
be safe, there is no problem with it,
every quarter
₹362500 will be deposited in your bank account, i.e. your
family's bank account. So
once in three months ₹3 lakhs i.e. one lakh per month is
enough for the expenses at that time.
Tell me in advance that you
have taken a policy from a certain policy bazaar, this is the
relationship manager number, you should
tell me all this in advance and keep it. Do you understand?
So you can change the tenure if you want.
This tenure
is the highest in this bank. So if you want the tenure of your choice, for example, for
10 years,
you can make an FD for 10 years.
After 10 years, you will get two crores
and every quarter
₹345000 will be deposited in your family's bank account.
Plan like this. All
this is not necessary. So whether you take the money at once
or
take it occasionally, it means that the person will benefit from both.  He says that he will give you
₹160,67,000 to ₹170,000 per month instead of giving crores at once. If you
take it at once, we will benefit.
This interest is something that we need.
Why is that? So if you are like this, plan
and remember that if you
are taking this term plan through the Kanaka Policy Bazaar website, there is a discount of up to 15%.
I
have given the link in the description below and also in the comments next to it. Do you
understand? You can
take it directly and there will be 24*7 climb
assistance. A dedicated
relationship manager will be with us. You
can call the number.
There is a number in the policy. So if you call, they will
talk to you. All these are there. And
besides that, it is not available online as an additional.
If you want to talk to them,
you can give an appointment and they will
come to their house and talk to them or
after you give the details, they will call you. You
can ask them for A to Z.
So if you want to take it,
take it. Like the discount is in the description below.  I
have given a link in the comments, you can check it if you want
and here is another one, he
says, "We have escaped there, 60 years is enough" and then he comes back here and says, "Hey, don't want 60 years,
put it up to 99 years" and then he
attracts you again.
Some people are tempted, "
Yes, let's put it up to 99 years, the
money will come, right?" Even if
we are not there, the family
will switch here unexpectedly. How much was it before? 1377.
How much was it if the switch was made?
3364. So you should avoid all this. So
the coverage is enough for 60 years. Is it okay
to change it like this? You should check online. It has
decreased. 1377. Similarly,
some other companies have an
option that they give, whatever your coverage is, we
will increase it by 5% every year, present
to year, so we will increase it by 5%, 5%, 5% every year.
I will give you an example.  I have written that
another company says that they will increase by 5% and it will continue to
increase for 20 years by
5% per year. So when 20 years come, that is, the 21st year, after
20 years, you have completed the policy and when the
21st year comes, your coverage will be a
bit of a force year. Which is good,
very good. Inflation will
increase, so if you compare it, it is good.
But I told you earlier that we should take inflation into account and take
20 times the starting amount.
So, starting amount is 20 times,
so there is no need. And here, okay, it would be better if it
increased by 5%, wouldn't it? But what they are saying is that they will increase our
premium by
₹1000 from the first month.
Here, the premium that we have to pay is ₹1377. So if you
look at it, if ₹1000 increases,
how much will it be? Then it will be
2377. Do you understand? But
the condition is that it will
increase from day one. If we start from day one,  You have to
pay ₹1000 extra but it will
increase by only 5% every year.
So you have kept it in mind in advance and
looked at more coverage, so
why pay extra? By
any chance, your income has
increased a lot from day one. Then
take a separate policy. If you want a 50 lakh policy,
take another policy from another company.
But you have to
tell the old company that you are taking it from another company and inform it by telling the old
company that you are taking it from another company as well.
Both of you should know. Do you understand that you already have a policy? Then do it like this. Proceed to the next. No more of all
this. Next,
we have come here again. We will stop here.
These are add-ons. Add-on
riders. Rider means extra benefit.
So far, we have seen the basic plan. This ₹137
basic plan. Now
we buy a car. We call the base model top-end.
So as we go to the top-end,
features come. This is also the same. So
first.  If you have taken care of one, you don't need this. Will
your wife take it
with you? Do you understand? So,
we are taking care of the coverage required to live with the whole family in mind in
advance, so we do
n't need this add-on. Second case
accidental death benefit, this is not
necessary at all. This is what I mean. Now, do you have
50 lakhs? If we
die in an accident, these 50 lakhs will be given along with these two CRs and these 50 locks as an extra. We have to
pay ₹287 more per month for that. We
thought in advance. We have calculated everything up to 20 times.
So why is there
no need for extra? That's what some people think.
Accidental disability is.
We can take that writer.
What does accidental disability mean? For example, there was an accident, my legs were
broken, especially my
hand was broken and one leg was
broken. We are lying on the bed at home.
So it is at the level of working.  We are alive, we die
If you want, you can add it.
Similarly, what diseases are there in the Next One Critical Illness
Benefit?
Here are 34 critical illnesses. Here are all
these diseases.
So in the future, these diseases will
come to us. Cancer, brain
surgery, etc. So even if these diseases come and we are
in a situation where we cannot work and are lying on the bed like that, we will
get money. Do you understand that this list is
only if the diseases on this list come? So
how much money do you need for this? For example,
you have cancer. You have cancer and
are lying on the bed. So you are not in a
situation where you can work. So
you know that cancer costs a lot.
Hospital expenses. So you have
checked 50 lakhs for
example. For example, suppose
many people in your family have inherited cancer from your grandparents.
Such people can check it. There is nothing wrong
because it may come. For example,
you have checked 50 lakhs.  So
how much do you have to pay per month?
Let's add this as an extra ₹1000. The add has
increased to
₹1377, which
is a bit ₹2380 because here we have
added a rider worth ₹50 lakhs, the critical illness rider.
So if we have any of these
diseases, the diseases mentioned, and
if we get those diseases and are
hospitalized, then this amount of money is ₹50
lakhs. The insurance company will give us ₹50 lakhs while we are
alive. For
example, if we give ₹50 lakhs, we are on bed rest, and
after a few months we die,
then the insurance company will give us ₹2 crores again. Do you
understand? If it is a dual
benefit, then it will be like this. So what I am saying is that you have asthma, you
drive a car, a bike, all these or you have a driving
job. It is definitely
not accidental death, accidental death, not a writer, but the
coverage will come only if you want it. We have already seen how much the family
needs.
Accidental disability.  If you
add the writer, similarly, if
someone in your family has had diseases before, your grandparents did not have them, let's say your father has
inherited a list of those diseases. If
you want, you can add this writer too.
That's all, but
I don't want to know more. You
can add all these and remember.
You can take the basic plan and then
add riders from another company if you want. That option is also there. Or, if
you take the basic plan and
add riders in the future,
you can
add them according to your situation. Do you understand that? If
you can take it like this, then review here and
give all your information and you can
take the policy directly. So what
I'm saying is, compare like this.
You can ask me for a good policy.
Many people are also saying this in the comments.
You can tell me what the good plan is. They say, "
We will take the best policy." So what
I'm saying is, don't say that
because it's best for me, it may not be
best for you. You are smoking.  I have a
habit, I don't have it, so change it,
premium change it, you have that job,
you don't have it, change it, so according to
our condition, according to the situation,
what is best, change it,
but finally what I say is
add the filter,
click on the climb settlement ratio high to so
now if you look at this, it says that
HDFC has got 100% and HDFC is
fine, it has been there since time immemorial but the premium is
high. If you look at the rest, if you
look at Axis Max Life, it is
99.7, the premium is low, you should
look at it, do you understand? Similarly, if you
look at IIC Proof, it is 992 but
1300 less, if you are good, you can take the good one. What
I say is that
whatever shows you the best in terms of price, in terms of
climb settlement ratio,
99 Anna is better, it does
n't need to be 100, 99 Anna is better and since when has this company been there, since when has it provided
services?  It
offers all this if you take care of it and if you want to
take it, so if you like this video, if you want to
take it directly, you can
take it on the Policy Bazaar website, it
doesn't matter. So you just
give the information and you will get a call,
talk to them or schedule it. If
you want to come home, you can
take it. There is a discount of up to 15%
and if you look at the plans,
depending on the age, if you look at the plans with a coverage of two crores, it is said that it will be in the middle of
600 to 700.
And since my age is high, I
put 997, so it
shows more, 2000 1400, it shows like this. Suppose
the age is low,
assume there are no habits, and there is a chance that these plans will come even less.
So
compare everything and take it. So if you
like this video, tell me if you liked it,
say if you liked it or not. So
if you want the links, they
are in the description below in my comments. Thank you so much
for watching. Jai Hind
[Music]